In this tutorial video, we use the 11th version of DOS Marvelous Designer.
If you need to learn the 10th version of Marvelous Designer, please watch the previous video.
In order to make it easier to learn, the DOS default standard mouse is used in this tutorial.
In Marvelous Designer, the particle diameter of the panel is set to 20.
When the particle diameter is lower, the number of frames is more, and the details of the clothing are more realistic, but the simulation speed will decrease.
Therefore, please reduce the particle diameter after adjusting the details such as the material and the component.
In addition, you can reduce the particle diameter little by little,
so that you can ensure that you can adjust the effect more quickly under certain details.
You can see that when the particle diameter is reduced to 5, the wrinkle effect of the clothing is already very realistic.
When the particle diameter of all panels is reduced to 3 or below, the simulation speed will be very slow, please be patient.
Now let's improve the clothing pattern together.
Use the adjustment panel tool to select all panels.
Then gradually reduce the particle diameter from 20 to 5.
When adjusting the clothing effect, we can modify the clothing panel and adjust the physical properties under the particle diameter of 15 or 10.
This can balance the simulation speed and effect.
The size of the panels is also relevant.
Smaller panels can be reduced to lower particle diameters because their network number is relatively small.
The overall network number in the 3D environment is one of the main factors that affect the speed of simulation.
After completion, press the control key to simulate and check the final wearing effect.
Since we are learning basic style T-shirts this time, the difference may not be very obvious,
but when you make more exquisite and more complex clothing, you will see the obvious difference.
Please save the project file.
The video of this issue of making T-shirts is over.